<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="ext_unlocker_v1">
  <copyright>
    Copyright 2021 Manuel Stoeckl

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
    copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
    to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
    the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
    and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
    all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
    FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
    AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
    LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS
    IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <interface name="ext_unlocker_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="protocol for a session (un)locker">
      This protocol provides an interface for letting a special lock screen
      client, which was created when the session was locked, communicate to
      the compositor that the session should be unlocked.
    </description>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy ext_unlocker_v1 object">
        Announce that this object will no longer be used.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="unlock">
      <description summary="unlock screen">
        Let the compositor know that it should unlock the screen.

        After this request has been sent by the client, sending it again shall
        have no effect.
      </description>
    </request>
  </interface>
</protocol>
